[music]
The Motor City experienced a flood of
emotions with two minutes to go in a
must-win matchup with the Pittsburgh
Steelers. Detroit's game-winning
touchdown with time expiring was called
back in the Lions Bowl in week 16 29-24.
Welcome to the Detroit Lions live
postgame show presented by Curado
Insurance alongside the Super Bowl champ
Lomis Brown. I'm Danny Rogers. Detroit's
playoff chances and their hopes are
almost non-existent. Packers only need
to win one of their two final games
against either the Ravens or the Vikings
and that will knock Detroit out. We
learned that two things rather can be
true tonight. That Aman Ross St. Brown
can complete a game-winning touchdown
pass back to Jared Goff who ran it in
for a touchdown. And we also learned
Aman Ross St. Brown committed an OPI on
this play, too. Here it is, Lis. It is
the play Lions fans will talk about for
a long time.
>> Yeah, Danny, the the one thing I want to
jump up on my soap box right now, the
one thing as a player, you want to be
able to control what happens on the
field. And I know these guys have to
feel robbed today that it was taken out
of their hands. It was just simply taken
out of their hands. Now, I'm not siding
on the side of wrong or right, but as a
player, you want to be able to control
what happens in the game, the results of
that game. And I just feel too many
times a day, it wasn't in the players
hands. It was taken out of their hands.
Like I say, Danny, be it wrong or right,
it shouldn't come down to that. I'm not
going to criticize any officials or
anything like that, but again, as a
player, you feel robbed when you don't
get the opportunity to control what
happens. I feel so bad for these Detroit
Lion players today because you work so
hard in your craft. You're such a
professional. This is a professional
league and you do everything you can
each and every week to come out and try
to get a victory. And when it's taken
from you by some somebody, it's just it
just doesn't feel good. So, I I'll leave
it at that. And, you know, yeah, I'll
just leave it at that.
>> Regardless of that final play, it is
very hard to win a ball game when you
only rush for 15 yards. That's what we
saw from the ground attack from
Detroit's David Montgomery and Jir
Gibbs. Gibbs 40 rushing yards over the
last two weeks. That is the bread and
butter of Detroit's offense and it has
been non-existent over almost the last
month.
>> No, you're right. And it has really hurt
our offense. I talked about coming into
this game how we just look so e uneven
offensively and it played out throughout
this game and like you say, we always
kind of ring our bell with our run game.
That's what we set our standards with.
That's what kind of gets our offense
going. And when we can't run the ball
and we're inadequate at running the ball
the way we were today, it just makes us
one-dimensional, Danny. And we're just
not the explosive offense that spreads
the ball around. So, yes, it's hurt us
the last couple of games, and we're
going to have to find a way to create
runs and get these guys going back if we
want to have some success on offense.
Defensively, on the flip side of that,
the run defense did not show up today,
allowing 230 yards to the fifth worst
run offense in the league. L
>> Danny, when you play so much on the
defensive side of the ball, I kind of
felt sorry for the defenders. They were
out there so much because we couldn't
get anything generated offensively. So
now you put a lot of pressure on your
defense to have to make stops and
continue to make stops. And eventually a
good offense, not they don't even have
to be a good offense. Offensives, they
will find ways to find cracks in your
defense. And you've seen it. Like you
say, our run game, which is normally
stout. I mean, those guys tried and
tried and tried, but eventually the dam
broke. And that's what happened against
us against the Pittsburgh Steelers
today.
>> In the second quarter, we saw a really
positive flash of light in wide
receiver. Isaac Tesla came up with a
gritty acrobatic catch in the end zone
to put Detroit up 10 to three. He ends
the day with 52 yards. Leads Detroit's
receivers. Longest catch of the day for
20. And that touchdown they will talk
about a lot. Tesla refuses to take his
name out of the conversation here in
Detroit.
>> And I wish I I wish it was a way we can
incorporate this young man more into the
offense because he is such a weapon. And
if you get the ball anywhere around him,
he's a guy that can come up with those
big uh big catches for you. That was a
huge touchdown catch that he came up
with. A huge contested touchdown pass
that he came up with. Almost came up
with a second one for us. But again, we
have to find a way to incorporate him
more into this offense because I just
think he's such a dynamic weapon for us
that we're underutilizing. Wide receiver
Khif Raymond came out of nowhere there
in the fourth quarter. Came up with a
big touchdown catch to put Detroit
within a score when they needed some big
plays. Raymond has stepped up 62
receiving yards on the day.
>> You're so right, Danny. He has. And
again, another guy would love to see get
more targets, uh, more catches, too,
because if you could get him in the open
space, man, he makes things happen for
us. He came up with some big catches for
us like you're saying. I mean, Khalif I
think is a weapon that again like Isaac
Tesla, someone that we have to try to
utilize, have to try to incorporate into
this offense more because you see
they're sitting on our stars. They know
about Almanra. They know about Jir. You
know, they know about J Mo, but I think
these other guys can be assets for us
too on the offensive side of the ball.
Mhm. That touchdown to Kie Framan was
Dan Campbell's 100th all-time fourth
down call.
>> Good for a touchdown. Jir Gibbs
continues to break records here in
Detroit despite the ground game not
getting going. Today he surpassed the
legend Barry Sanders for the most
touchdowns in a player's first three
seasons. I talked with Gibbs earlier
this week. He told me this is the only
record so far that actually carries
weight for him. So, it means a lot that
he was able to go out there and get that
touchdown today.
>> I know he wish it would have been in a
victory to get this record, but he
should cherish this record because like
you say, he surpassed one of the all
time, I say the all-time greatest
running back to play this game. Uh, he's
put his name in elite company when you
talk about Barry Sanders. So, you know,
he should be proud of what he has
accomplished in his first three years in
the league. And Danny, it's a lot more
to go. So that's the thing that we have
to look forward to is that he's just
getting started.
>> There were seven different receivers
here in this game that caught a football
from Jared Goth. Six of them had 40 or
more receiving yards. It was wide
receiver by committee tonight. Lis we
saw that almost work down the stretch
with Jameson Williams and Alman Ross St.
Brown getting going. What stifled the
pass game for the most part?
>> Yeah. So some untimely plays that
happened to us. couple of penalties that
were untimely at that point. But to be
honest with you, I'll be straight up.
Jared just didn't look comfortable back
there either. I mean, he, you know,
yeah, he got it going towards the second
part of the game, but the first half, he
just didn't look comfortable. Whether it
was Pittsburgh with their pass rush that
got him off his spot, but I don't know,
it just didn't seem like the same Jared
Golf. And again, I can contribute a lot
of that to us not being able to run the
ball. You run the ball, you keep the
defense on their heels, then I think you
able to do a lot more things. I was glad
to see the tight ends get incorporated
into the offense more this uh tonight.
But again, Jared just didn't look as
smooth, as even as he has been looking
all season long.
>> A part of that has to be that Detroit
ran three different centers in this
game. Great play.
>> Golf was sacked three times and
Pittsburgh rallied off nine quarterback
hits throughout this one. So an
uncomfortable day for golf. We'll talk
more about that coming up next in our
Detroit Lions live postgame show
presented by Curado Insurance.
>> Guys, your prior success has put you at
the top of the power rankings list.
That's a good thing, right?
>> Well, just means you've gone from the
underdog to the favorite.
>> But those expectations come from prior
success, so that's okay.
>> What about Cure? Where [music] do you
guys rank on the power list? Actually,
we just got named by Forbes as one of
the best car insurance companies in
America.
>> Now you're the [music] favorite.
>> Guess we have a lot in common.
>> Go Cure.
>> Go Lions.
>> Cure Auto Insurance. Drive well.
>> Detroit Lions Live is brought to you by
Cure Auto Insurance. Log on to cure.com
to see how you can save.
Lis, we heard a lot from defensive
coordinator Kelvin Shepard this week
that he was putting a lot of the faults
on his back in terms of this Detroit
defense not able to nail down opponents
and take away what they do best. Aaron
Rogers had a pretty good day. That run
game though, 230 for the fifth worst run
rushing attack in the league speaks
volumes as to where this defense is in
Detroit right now. And what kind of
disturbed me a little bit in the run
game, Danny, too, is that if you think
about both of those 45 yardd runs from
the their running back, I mean, it was
nobody out there. I mean, it was really
nobody out there. Nice scheme that
Pittsburgh ran, but it was no contained
out there. And either to me, either
that's miscommunication,
you know, guys not knowing where they
needed to be at, cuz I don't think they
just out physical us, especially on the
edges. So, that's what was a little
disturbing, especially like I say on
those two 45 yard touchdown runs uh that
uh Pittsburgh got today. But Caval Shep
is right. When your team gets beat in
the run game, that normally means the
other team was more physical than you.
And you never want to hear those words
as a a defensive coordinator that your
team got out physical. But that happened
today to us.
>> Head coach Dan Campbell is standing by
at the podium. We've got a few answers
from him on his team's week 16 loss.
>> The level if you're disappointed the it
looked like the Steelers pushed you guys
around a bit. They ran the ball better,
stopped the run, physical. Is that what
stings you?
>> I can't argue with that. I mean, they
look the ground game says it. I mean,
you know, they're they're rushing now.
They rushed it. You know, they had a lot
more carries. Um, and some of that was,
you know, our defense is on the field
for a while and, you know, when you're
able to convert, stay on the field a
while, then you can, you can kind of
bounce from run to run to run to, you
know, play pass to it just opens your
offense up and that's what they're able
to do. And, you know, they can, you
know, you run a play, you get the look,
you run a play, you get the look, you
run the the opposite of that and see how
they respond, and then you get a look.
And, uh, we just, we weren't able to do
it, and they were. And, uh, and yeah, I
mean, I I can't. They got after us. Um,
I mean, they rushed for over 200 yards
and uh only 15 for us.
>> Did you see it?
>> I didn't see it. I couldn't even see it,
man. I was uh I was looking at the
protection and and golf and then I saw
the catch and that was
>> decision to pitch the ball to golf. me
regardless of what what
>> heads he play man and he went down and
and just to stay alive for the last play
man I mean that's that's what sane is
he's a he's a freaking smart instinctive
player um one more shot um we thought
>> uh call a few plays earlier where Tesla
was called for OPI on the same run they
said he it was you know that it was OPI
He ran into the defensive back or
whoever it was. Um, which you I mean you
there's nothing you can do. They see
what they see. Um, and I have I I didn't
see that one either, so I have no idea.
>> Dan, when you're analyzing dissecting
this game, do you regret not kicking a
field goal early in the game?
>> No.
How much you know of the substitutions
that you have to make so many on the
offensive line in the defensive back
field. There will seem to be some
confusion on some plays where the
safeties are supposed to go and all
that. Is that just take a toll when
you're constantly rejiggering your
lineup every week and having to teach
guys kind of on the
>> No, I don't. You know what? Here's it. I
>> guys, your prior success has put you at
the top of [music] the power rankings
list. That's a good thing, right?
>> Well, just means you've gone from the
underdog to the favorite.
>> But those expectations come from prior
success, so that's okay. [music]
>> What about Cure? Where do you guys rank
on the power list? Actually, we just got
named by Forbes as one of the best car
insurance companies in America.
>> Now you're the favorite.
>> Guess we have a lot in common.
>> Go Cure. [music]
>> Go Lions.
>> Cure Auto Insurance. Drive well.
>> Detroit Lions Live is brought to you by
Cure Auto Insurance. Log on to cure.com
to see how you can save.
Coming up next for the Detroit Lions, a
Thursday kickoff. Minneapolis at the
Vikings place 4:30 on Christmas Day.
Don't you want some presents under your
tree with that one? Could be a good
present.
>> I would love
>> No bow or tag, but it's wrapped.
>> I need one too, BF.
>> Maybe just a gift bag. Actually,
[laughter]
the present won't be wrapped, but
there's a gift bag that that
>> I'll take it. I will take it. I will
take it. Yes. As you say, we travel to
Minneapolis to take on those Minnesota
Vikings, a team that kind of helped put
us in the situation that we're in right
now. So, I think we owe them. That would
be such a nice present.
>> That'd be a great little redemption
there. Quarterback JJ McCarthy left the
game earlier today with a hand injury.
So, he'll more than likely be
questionable heading into this one.
Lions have alternated losses for about
>> Yes. Well, in the last 10 weeks, they
haven't lost back-to-back games in
almost three years. That streak ends
here tonight with a gut-wrenching fourth
quarter game-winning touchdown on the
line that was called back by an OPI. How
do you just get up, wake up tomorrow,
and how do these guys, these Detroit
Lions, just find something to play for
moving forward?
>> Danny, I'm not going to lie, it's going
to be hard. It really is. It's going to
be hard because you still have something
to play for. there's still a outside
chance that we could get in there.
>> 6% chance.
>> But so you hang your hat on that 6%
chance. You go back to the drawing board
and you just clean up what you didn't do
well tonight. You know, you try to clean
up those penalties. You try to clean up
some of the things that prevented you,
especially on the offensive side of the
ball of being as proficient as we've
been throughout this year. It's just
strange how we've had hung our hat on
being a great run team that set
everything else off of that and these
last couple of weeks haven't been good
for us in the run. And the other thing
Danny is third down, I'm sorry, third
quarter that's been terrible for us
coming out of halftime. So, it's
something that uh Dan Campbell, the
coaching staff, the players, they're
going to have to make an adjustment and
fi figure out a way to come out in the
third quarter and put up points, you
know, stop teams and do what they have
to do to make sure that we have success
on that game day.
>> Last two third quarters for Detroit have
been scoreless today. Only able to run
three plays and one ended in a sack
safety for the Pittsburgh Steelers. All
right, for Lis Brown, I'm Danny Rogers.
Thanks so much for tuning in to our
Detroit Lions live postgame show
presented by Curado Insurance. Detroit
Falls to Pittsburgh here in week 16. The
final 29-24.
Got to play for the love of the game
probably here moving forward. Lis, we'll
see you next week in Minneapolis for a
Christmas Day showdown.
Heat. Heat. N. [music]
Heat. Heat. N.
[music]
>> [music]